let indianGKQuestions = {
    time: 30, // in minutes
    questions: [{
        question: "1. Prime minister of India is ____?",
        option1: "Rahul Gandhi",
        option2: "me",
        option3: "Narendra modi",
        option4: "You",
        correctresponse: "Narendra modi",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "2. Which river is considered the lifeline of the Indian state of Jammu and Kashmir?",
        option1: "Ganga",
        option2: "Yamuna",
        option3: "Brahmaputra",
        option4: "Indus",
        correctresponse: "Indus",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "3. Who was the first woman Prime Minister of India?",
        option1: "Indira Gandhi",
        option2: "Sonia Gandhi",
        option3: "Mayawati",
        option4: "Pratibha Patil",
        correctresponse: "Indira Gandhi",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "4. What is capital of bihar?",
        option1: "I am capital",
        option2: "Patna",
        option3: "Gaya",
        option4: "Madhya Pradesh",
        correctresponse: "Patna",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "5. The Red Fort is located in which Indian city?",
        option1: "Mumbai",
        option2: "Kolkata",
        option3: "New Delhi",
        option4: "Jaipur",
        correctresponse: "New Delhi",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "6. Who wrote the Indian national anthem, 'Jana Gana Mana'?",
        option1: "Rabindranath Tagore",
        option2: "Mahatma Gandhi",
        option3: "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        option4: "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        correctresponse: "Rabindranath Tagore",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "7. What is the currency of India?",
        option1: "Rupee",
        option2: "Taka",
        option3: "Rupiah",
        option4: "Rial",
        correctresponse: "Rupee",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "8. Who is known as the 'Father of the Indian Nation'?",
        option1: "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        option2: "Mahatma Gandhi",
        option3: "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        option4: "Subhas Chandra Bose",
        correctresponse: "Mahatma Gandhi",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "9. Which is the highest civilian award in India?",
        option1: "Padma Vibhushan",
        option2: "Padma Shri",
        option3: "Bharat Ratna",
        option4: "Padma Bhushan",
        correctresponse: "Bharat Ratna",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "10. Who composed the Indian national song 'Vande Mataram'?",
        option1: "Sarojini Naidu",
        option2: "Bankim Chandra Chattopadhyay",
        option3: "Rabindranath Tagore",
        option4: "Mahatma Gandhi",
        correctresponse: "Bankim Chandra Chattopadhyay",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "11. Which is the longest river in India?",
        option1: "Ganga",
        option2: "Yamuna",
        option3: "Brahmaputra",
        option4: "Godavari",
        correctresponse: "Ganga",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "12. The Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) was founded in which year?",
        option1: "1969",
        option2: "1972",
        option3: "1962",
        option4: "1975",
        correctresponse: "1969",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "13. Which Indian state is known as the 'Spice Garden of India'?",
        option1: "Kerala",
        option2: "Karnataka",
        option3: "Gujarat",
        option4: "Andhra Pradesh",
        correctresponse: "Kerala",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "14. Who is the first woman to climb Mount Everest from India?",
        option1: "Arunima Sinha",
        option2: "Bachendri Pal",
        option3: "Santosh Yadav",
        option4: "Malavath Purna",
        correctresponse: "Bachendri Pal",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "15. Which is the largest freshwater lake in India?",
        option1: "Chilika Lake",
        option2: "Wular Lake",
        option3: "Dal Lake",
        option4: "Loktak Lake",
        correctresponse: "Wular Lake",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "16. What is the name of the highest peak in India?",
        option1: "Mount Everest",
        option2: "Kangchenjunga",
        option3: "Nanda Devi",
        option4: "K2",
        correctresponse: "Kangchenjunga",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "17. Which city is known as the 'Pink City' of India?",
        option1: "Jaipur",
        option2: "Agra",
        option3: "Udaipur",
        option4: "Jodhpur",
        correctresponse: "Jaipur",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "18. Who was the first Indian woman to win an Olympic medal?",
        option1: "P.T. Usha",
        option2: "Saina Nehwal",
        option3: "Karnam Malleswari",
        option4: "Mary Kom",
        correctresponse: "Karnam Malleswari",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "19. Which Indian state is known as the 'Land of Forests'?",
        option1: "Assam",
        option2: "Madhya Pradesh",
        option3: "Uttarakhand",
        option4: "Arunachal Pradesh",
        correctresponse: "Madhya Pradesh",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "20. Who was the first Indian woman to win the Miss World title?",
        option1: "Sushmita Sen",
        option2: "Aishwarya Rai",
        option3: "Priyanka Chopra",
        option4: "Rita Faria",
        correctresponse: "Reita Faria",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "21. Capital of Bihar is _____?",
        option1: "Punjab",
        option2: "Patna",
        option3: "Patliputra",
        option4: "gaya",
        correctresponse: "Patna",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "22. Who is known as the Father of the Indian Constitution?",
        option1: "Mahatma Gandhi",
        option2: "Jawaharlal Nehru",
        option3: "B.R. Ambedkar",
        option4: "Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel",
        correctresponse: "B.R. Ambedkar",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "23. What is the capital city of Bhutan??",
        option1: "Punjab",
        option2: "Haryana",
        option3: "Thimphu",
        option4: "Paro",
        correctresponse: "Thimphu",
        time: 1
    },
    {
        question: "24. What is the capital city of Nepal?",
        option1: "Kathmandu",
        option2: "Pokhara",
        option3: "Biratnagar",
        option4: "Birgunj",
        correctresponse: "Kathmandu",
        time: 1
    },

    {
        question: "25. Mount Everest, the world's highest mountain peak, is located in which country?",
        option1: "India",
        option2: "China",
        option3: "Nepal",
        option4: "Bhutan",
        correctresponse: "Nepal",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "26. Which planet is known as the morning star or evening star?",
        option1: "Mars",
        option2: "Venus",
        option3: "Mercury",
        option4: "Jupiter",
        correctresponse: "Venus",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "27. Who is the author of the Harry Potter book series?",
        option1: "J.K. Rowling",
        option2: "Stephen King",
        option3: "Dan Brown",
        option4: "Terry Pratchett",
        correctresponse: "J.K. Rowling",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "28. What is the largest desert in the world?",
        option1: "Sahara Desert",
        option2: "Gobi Desert",
        option3: "Arabian Desert",
        option4: "Kalahari Desert",
        correctresponse: "Sahara Desert",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "29. Which animal is known as the 'Ship of the Desert'?",
        option1: "Camel",
        option2: "Horse",
        option3: "Donkey",
        option4: "Dromedary",
        correctresponse: "Camel",
        time: 1
      },
      {
        question: "30. What is the national bird of the United States?",
        option1: "Eagle",
        option2: "Bald Eagle",
        option3: "Hawk",
        option4: "Falcon",
        correctresponse: "Bald Eagle",
        time: 1
      }
    ]
}

export default indianGKQuestions;